So this is a comparison video between HDFC
Ego Aftermass Seeker and Care Health Supreme
Plan. We will talk about the
eligibility criteria of both, what are the
similarities between the two, and
what are the differences between the two. We will also
talk about the premium. Before starting the video,
I would like to introduce myself.
My name is Goodlink. I am a
Certified Financial Planner. I have been
associated with Institutions for the last 18 years and
every week I bring videos for you so that
your personal financial life becomes happy
because the tagline of the company
is Creating a Wealth of Happiness.
Quick reminder before starting the video.
If you have not yet subscribed to our channel,
please do so so that you get the right
information. Let's
move on to the video. HDFC will
first talk about the claim
settlement ratio of both and their claim ratio.
HDFC's claim settlement ratio
is 95%. Their claim ratio is 74.6%.  The
claim settlement ratio is 87.1%
and the denial claim ratio is 65.07%. So,
before starting the comparison of both the plans,
I would like to share with you the benefits
of both the plans.
In HDFC's plan, you have a benefit of
2x, which is 2x from the one you take.
Whatever number of installments you take, whatever your benefit will be,
it will be counted 2x. If you are talking about Super, then it will be
3x,
and for Super, our detailed
video is already available, you can refer.
Secondly, there is a Plus benefit in it, which works
like a loyalty addition.
You get 50% of the claim in the
next year and 50% in the next year
when you renew the policy
and there is no clawback in it. This is a
relief for you always, meaning if the 2x
policy becomes 3x, then it will remain 3x.
If the 3x policy becomes 4x in 3 years.  IT
bill reimbursement 4x Now let's talk about Kerala
Supreme's Yes, here the no
claim bonus which is called cumulative bonus is
a rider of NC Super which you
can add in which your maximum time bill
will be ₹500% if you do not make a claim then it will go up to 500%
once it reaches 500% then there will be
no loss so this is Yes Kerala Supreme
plan now let's compare both the plans
first we will talk about eligibility
criteria minimum entry is ahead minimum
entry is ahead in HDFC and that in Optimum Care the
child's minimum is 91 days and the child can
continue in the policy till 25 years
as dependent after that the
policy will be split the minimum entry is ahead for
adults is 18 and maximum is 65 now let's talk about
Kerala Supreme, the child's minimum is ahead 91
days and the
child can continue in the dependent policy till maximum 24 years
adult's minimum is ahead  Age 18
and maximum entry age 60 years Policy
Type You can also take Individual, Family, Floor Term,
Multi Individual policy
Time Short Time Short HDFC EGO
Optimus is available in Kar Minimum five Lux
Maximum up to 2 crore You can also take policy
available for ₹57 Lux policy 10 Air
policy 10 Air policy is available 1 Air, 2 Air and
3 Air If you take Multi 10 Air policy in which
you pay the premium for 2 years and 3 years upfront, then the
company
gives you some discount and yes I
would like to tell one thing here that
you can take the benefit of 80d, even if you are taking Multi,
then whatever premium you pay will be
divided by the number of years, that means
if you have paid the premium for 2 years, by
dividing it by two you will get the benefit of 80d
Room Rent There
is no room rent in both the plans, you can opt for any room,
bonus
is your benefit plus benefit plus  This means
that your sum assured will increase by 50% in the next year
and the next year will
also increase by 50%, so 1x will be added,
100% will be added in two years, so this has
nothing to do with the claim, this is
irrespective of clean and clear, so
your cumulative bonus is in the screen, if you do
not take the claim then cumulative bonus of
50% will be added to the maximum IT bill of 100% and
it will not be reduced, even if you take the claim,
day care treatment is covered,
day care is there in both the plans, where there is
no need for 24 hours hospitalization,
domiciliary hospitalization is covered,
both the plans have short term insurance,
you are taking treatment at home because of two reasons,
one is that there is
no space available in the hospital, secondly the patient
is so critical that he cannot go to the hospital,
home care treatment is covered, OPD is
not available in both the plans, both will talk about restoration, it is
your restoration  If the base is always
exhausted, then
this restore gets triggered once in HDFC EGO Optimus Seeker.
Here, there is an option to
add unlimited restore benefit rider. If
you want to do so,
you
can add on unlimited restore benefit rider at a very low cost, at a nominal cost, meaning
multiple number of times refill will be triggered
equal to base time shot and you
can do it for any problem.
In Care Supreme, refill benefits are available but
unlimited number of times for other
illnesses or different illnesses,
you can do it for both, free and post
hospital expenses, that is,
expenses before leaving the hospital and after coming home from the hospital, also in
Rainbow, you can cover the expenses of 60 days before and 180 days remaining, in
both the
policies emergency road ambulance will be done
at HDFC, but road ambulance
in Care Supreme, if your policy is less than 15 lakhs, then the maximum amount is
Rs.  Whatever the
expense is, the maximum is ₹10,000. If it
is above ₹15 lakh, the actual limit on it is up to ₹5 lakh.
Emergency and ambulance
are covered in HDFC Ego Optimus Seeker, up to ₹
5 lakh and Care Supreme. You
can avail additional rider
up to ₹5 lakh by paying an additional premium. Modern
treatment is available in both the plans. Organ
donor expenses are also available in both the plans.
Eye consultation, so in HDFC Ego
Optimus, eye consultation
is available. First 51 critical illnesses are available.
If you take Super Seeker, then
one side is being covered with an international doctor
and in Care Supreme, you get unlimited medical
consultations. Maternity benefits,
maternity benefits are not available in both the plans.
AYUSH coverage, Ayurveda,
Unani, Siddha, Homeopathy,
their hospital
is an optional rider in both the plans, which you can avail by paying an additional premium.
Wellness benefits, so  There are wellness
benefits. The more active our
lifestyle is, the more the insurance company
gives you some discounts. This rider
or in-belt feature is available in
HDFC and is not available in Warehouse Supreme.
This is a rider available in India. It is an optional add-on.
You can add it by paying premium, so that
you
get a discount on the annual premium. If you maintain an active lifestyle, through the
annual deductible, so the
option of annual allowance
is available in HDFC Option Care, through
which you can reduce your premium. That is,
if you take a deductible of Rs 25,000 and Rs 1 lakh, your
premium will be reduced by a maximum of
50%. So, such an option
is not available in Care Help. The base premium
in both the plans is John 1 and John 2.
You will be charged premium according to the zone in which you live.
Now let's talk about waiting
periods. There are some waiting periods.
In your health insurance policy, the
initial waiting period is 30 days.
30 days in two plans.  The days
waiting period which we
also call slow growing illnesses is not there, there is a
waiting period of 24 months for 2 years in both the
policies for existing conditions waiting
period, so in SDMCAR Optimus Seeker there will be no waiting period for existing
conditions
but it is 36 months, Clear Health Supreme has a
waiting period of 48 months but free existing condition
consumables are there, so
consumables are there in your but
in HDFC EGO Optimus Seeker all the consumables are
non payable items,
in Supreme you can take a rider by making a claim sale, due to which
your consumable items will be covered,
so now let's talk about optional riders
which you can add in your policy,
in HDFC Optimus Seeker you
can take Unlimited Restore Benefit Rider,
you can add Critical Illness in which
this looms up benefit bill can be paid out in case
of 51 critical illnesses you  You
can add as many illnesses as you are taking in hospitals, which
means you will get daily cash benefit.
You can add limit according to the number of days you are in the hospital.
Care Health Supreme has optional riders for
your wellness benefit,
which will give you discount. You
can add super, where your no
claim bonus will go up to 100%, every year maximum 500%
and 500% will not be deductible. If
you make a claim, your policy will
reach 6x. If you take the cumulative bonus super
rider, then you can also add annual health
checkup through the rider. You can also add
emergency ambulance
through the rider. There is a limit of 5. You can take Clean Shield Have
Rider, you can also take non-fi items. So
lastly, let's talk about the premium schemes of
both the companies.
So these were the details from my side about HDFC
EGO Optimum and Care Health
Supreme Plan. I hope you found this video
useful and if you found it useful then you  You
can share this with friends and family.
Thank you letter. If you have any
questions or want to give any feedback,
please share in the comment area. You
can also share it on our WhatsApp number
and email ID. A quick reminder before going,
if you have not yet subscribed to our channel, do
subscribe so that you get the right information and at the
right
time. We will meet soon in the next video.
Stay safe, take care, bye.
We will talk if we
get time.